<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tribal Spread</title><link>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Tribal Spread</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2020, Yash Bhutwala; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 10:05:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yashbhutwala.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultimate guide to right sizing pods in Kubernetes - Requests, Limits, HPA, VPA</title><link>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/post/2020-09-18-right-sizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 10:05:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/post/2020-09-18-right-sizing/</guid><description>Table of Contents Background Problem Statement Solutions Day 1 Solution Recommendations for initial limits and requests Notes on load testing Day 2 Solution: VPA and its gaps Links Background When it comes to handling scale for a workload, you get 3 knobs in Kubernetes: requests, limits, and replicas. Kubernetes pods specify their CPU and memory needs via resource requests. CPU resources are measured in virtual cores or more commonly in millicores, e.</description></item><item><title>Deploy your own blog for free using Hugo + GitHub Pages + GitHub Action</title><link>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/post/2020-09-15-hugo-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:28:50 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/post/2020-09-15-hugo-github-pages/</guid><description>Table of Contents Immediately useful links Background links Source code for this blog lives on master branch here. The actual assets for the website live on the gh-pages branch here and is posted automatically via the GitHub Action here.
Immediately useful links hugo-clarity theme hugo-clarity github repo GitHub Action for setting up Hugo make sure to do &amp;ldquo;Hugo extended version&amp;rdquo; GitHub Action for deploying to GitHub Pages make sure to enable manual deployments to enable debugging make sure to point to gh-pages branch in repo settings for GitHub Pages Background links GitHub docs about creating GitHub Pages Hugo Themes Hugo Quick Start Docs</description></item><item><title>dotcli: query graph data written in Graphviz DOT language</title><link>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/post/2020-09-14-dotcli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 12:28:50 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/post/2020-09-14-dotcli/</guid><description>Table of Contents Problem Statement Solution Examples Links Problem Statement In a microservices oriented world, applications might be split up over 10s, 100s, 1000s of service containers. Often, devs, QAs, performance testing teams want to just develop against and test a subset of these microservices. So, instead of spinning up the entire application and all its 100s of containers, it makes sense to only spin up a subset of these services that represent specific &amp;ldquo;whole&amp;rdquo; functionalities.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yashbhutwala.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Yash Bhutwala. I am an Engineering and Thought Leader. My interests range from software, distributed systems, Bitcoin, Go to cricket, workouts, leadership, culture and more. You will see me around trying to learn new stuffs always, and writing some experiences here. If you want to reach out and provide me some feedback, or ask something from anything I wrote here please please please! Feel free to direct message me.</description></item></channel></rss>